<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mousse on Mario&#39;z Eats</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/mousse/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mousse on Mario&#39;z Eats</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 11:35:07 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/mousse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Matcha Tart</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/raspberrymatchatart/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 11:35:07 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/raspberrymatchatart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7838/46544995685_43063d0632_c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Raspberry matcha tarts cross&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tarts are quite delicious so I wanted to pair something with matcha. It takes quite a while, so just a heads up! The rich shortcrust is adapted from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thekitchn.com/how-to-make-pate-sablee-for-classic-tarts-and-pastries-222311&#34;&gt;The Kitchn&lt;/a&gt;. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember where the other recipes originally came from. I&amp;rsquo;ve been adapting them each iteration. This recipe is for about 7-8 3in tarts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Rich Shortcrust Pastry:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;224 g butter (2 sticks), room temp&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;84 g powdered sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 large egg yolk&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;6 g salt (1/2 tsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;142 g all purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;20 g milk, if needed&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beat butter and sugar until creamy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beat in egg yolks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add flour and salt, while mixing at low speed. Don&amp;rsquo;t overmix. If it looks dry, add some milk.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chill dough in plastic wrap for at least 1 hour in the fridge. I did overnight.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Let soften on counter. Once soft, fraction into smaller pieces. Roll out between two sheets of wax paper.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut out circles and fit to tart molds/ rings. For my tart rings, I did two separate cut outs. One circle for the base and one strip of dough for the side.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use a fork to make lots of holes in the base and then chill for 30 minutes or so. Preheat the oven to 375F.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bake for about 40 minutes. Check in on them around the 30 min mark.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Matcha Coconut Cream:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>cherimoyamangotart</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/cherimoyamangotart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 17:24:27 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/cherimoyamangotart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A short while ago, I finally got to try the tarts from b. patisserie. And wow. Wowowow. The black sesame coconut one I got was so delicious. I knew I wanted to try something like that, so I bought some ring molds and gave it a shot. Lots of things failed, but finally got a few that were presentable. The mango flavor of the cream base didn&amp;rsquo;t come across at all. I&amp;rsquo;ll post an edited recipe that may work? The original one called for&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Sesame Chiffon and Matcha Mousse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/blacksesamematchachiffon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 13:55:47 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/blacksesamematchachiffon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4212/35905895225_886436d095_h.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Black Sesame Matcha Chiffon Cake&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently saw some adorable little chiffon cake pans and bought a few. I knew the center would be the perfect vessle for a type of filling. Decided on a mousse. For this particular one, I set it a bit too much for my liking, but was still really happy with the flavor. The mousse is super liquidy when you first prepare it. But after a short while in the fridge/ freezer, it firms up nicely. It becomes a great texture after being in the fridge overnight. But yeah, this mousse was great and I&amp;rsquo;ll definitely use this recipe again. The mousse recipe was from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thespruce.com/matcha-green-tea-mousse-2031119&#34;&gt;The Spruce&lt;/a&gt; and the chiffon cake was adapated from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.justonecookbook.com/green-tea-chiffon-cake/&#34;&gt;Just One Cookbook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mousses</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/mousse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 15:24:07 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/mousse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wish I was good at making mousses. I&amp;rsquo;m not. But I have a few recipes that work well enough. I wish I knew how to make the kind that legit Russian bakers use in their mousse cakes. OH WELLS. I adapted the mousse cake mousses from &lt;a href=&#34;http://verdadedesabor.blogspot.ru/2016/04/torta-rubus.html&#34;&gt;Verdade de sabor: torta rubus&lt;/a&gt;. Not sure where I first got the tart mousse recipe from :o.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For these, you can easily replace flavors by subbing out flavors/ powders/ purees.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
