<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Raspberry on Mario&#39;z Eats</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/raspberry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Raspberry on Mario&#39;z Eats</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 11:35:07 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/raspberry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Matcha Tart</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/raspberrymatchatart/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 11:35:07 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/raspberrymatchatart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7838/46544995685_43063d0632_c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Raspberry matcha tarts cross&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tarts are quite delicious so I wanted to pair something with matcha. It takes quite a while, so just a heads up! The rich shortcrust is adapted from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thekitchn.com/how-to-make-pate-sablee-for-classic-tarts-and-pastries-222311&#34;&gt;The Kitchn&lt;/a&gt;. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember where the other recipes originally came from. I&amp;rsquo;ve been adapting them each iteration. This recipe is for about 7-8 3in tarts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Rich Shortcrust Pastry:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;224 g butter (2 sticks), room temp&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;84 g powdered sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 large egg yolk&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;6 g salt (1/2 tsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;142 g all purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;20 g milk, if needed&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beat butter and sugar until creamy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beat in egg yolks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add flour and salt, while mixing at low speed. Don&amp;rsquo;t overmix. If it looks dry, add some milk.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chill dough in plastic wrap for at least 1 hour in the fridge. I did overnight.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Let soften on counter. Once soft, fraction into smaller pieces. Roll out between two sheets of wax paper.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut out circles and fit to tart molds/ rings. For my tart rings, I did two separate cut outs. One circle for the base and one strip of dough for the side.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use a fork to make lots of holes in the base and then chill for 30 minutes or so. Preheat the oven to 375F.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bake for about 40 minutes. Check in on them around the 30 min mark.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Matcha Coconut Cream:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charcoal Raspberry Creampuffs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/charcoalraspberrycreampuffs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 10:06:59 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/charcoalraspberrycreampuffs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4259/35321096582_ac41da8609_h.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Charcoal Raspberry Cream Puffs&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lol. Continuing on with that activated charcoal trend :p. It makes all the colors pop! Charcoal makes batters more runny, so you might even want to use less. And it also drastically changes baking time for at least this recipe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Charcoal Choux Pastry: [for about 25-30 cream puffs]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;200 g water&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;125 g milk&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;112 g butter (stick, cut into small pieces)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;4 g salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;4 g sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;150 g flour&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;12 g activated charcoal&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3 large eggs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 400F.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add milk, water, butter, sugar, and salt into a saucepan and bring to boil. You want your butter to have melted prior to boiling, so make sure you cut up the stick of butter into small pieces.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sift out the flour and add the charcoal. I whisk this up to make a nice blended mixture&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Take the saucepan off the heat, and add in the sifted flour and charcoal. Stir in (wooden spoon is best) the flour until everything comes together into a ball.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Return to heat and stir vigorously until you start to see some dried residue on the side (3-4 minutes minutes). Sometimes if I&amp;rsquo;m not sure, I just stir for longer. In my experience, having less liquid in that dough is better.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Transfer the dough into a bowl and beat until steam no longer rises. If it&amp;rsquo;s in a stand mixer, until the bowl is no longer hot to the touch. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to scramble your eggs that you&amp;rsquo;re about to incorporate.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;One at a time, beat in the eggs. Be patient and don&amp;rsquo;t add them all at once.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dough/ batter should now be a bit droopy. Add to a piping bag with a large round tip.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pipe you desired size onto a silpat or parchment paper (though, silpats are awesome and everyone should use them).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grab a small bowl of water and using your finger dipped in water, flatten all the points which resulted from piping them. Those little points will burn in the oven, so flatten those and any other pointy edges which may be on your silpat.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Charcoal really changed up the baking parameters. They take much longer and you can&amp;rsquo;t see if it&amp;rsquo;s browning or not, so you have to press lightly to see if they&amp;rsquo;re solid yet. Bake for 35 minutes at 400F. Then drop the temperature down to 300F and bake for 20 more minutes.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Opening the oven during the first 30 minutes will cause them to collapse on themselves. You want the puffs to form a solid structure.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Now open the oven and without pulling out the pan, press lightly on the puffs to see if they&amp;rsquo;re solid. If they are, you want to stab holes in the bottom. I have a long pointy piping tip that I now use, but I used to use a chopstick and that worked perfectly fine. 1. Go through and poke holes in the solid cream puffs and then put them back onto the pan on their side. Removing the pan from the oven will cause the ones that aren&amp;rsquo;t fully set yet to collapse, so make sure to leave it in.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If all the puffs have been stabbed, then you can bake for maybe 15 more minutes at 250F. You can turn off oven and leave them in to dry out even more.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If the cream puffs aren&amp;rsquo;t fully baked yet, drop the temperature down to 250F and bake for another 15 minutes. After that, check back every 10 minutes to see. Once they are all stabbed, turn off oven and leave the pan inside for the puffs to dry out.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once the insides have dried (you can check a tester), take the pan out and let fully cool.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Raspberry Diplomat Cream:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(Not 100% sure this is what it&amp;rsquo;s called)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Raspberry Layer Cake</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/chocolateraspberrycake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 11:55:16 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/chocolateraspberrycake/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Macarons</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/raspberrymacarons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 11:35:07 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/raspberrymacarons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4262/35425799446_3694a0b48c_h.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Raspberry Macarons&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE 2019&lt;/em&gt; I now use 55 g almond flour, 50 g powdered sugar, 45 g egg whites, 45 g granulated sugar and bake for 25 min at 285F.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update Jan 2020&lt;/strong&gt;, lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing 305F for 20min. once again you just nead to learn your oven (going to leave this recipe at 285 though). See my notes in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mariozeats.com/post/macarons/&#34;&gt;General Macarons Recipe&lt;/a&gt; for the most up to date.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
