<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Other on Mario&#39;z Eats</title>
    <link>https://www.mariozeats.com/categories/other/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Other on Mario&#39;z Eats</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 11:35:17 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.mariozeats.com/categories/other/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Useful Recipes</title>
      <link>https://www.mariozeats.com/post/usefulrecipes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 11:35:17 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mariozeats.com/post/usefulrecipes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest uses of my blog is for me to find recipes so I don&amp;rsquo;t forget them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While I usually search to find a dessert that has a component I need, here are direct links to those base recipes:&#xA;Switching out flavors for these recipes is super easy. Literally just add it. They&amp;rsquo;re pretty robust and won&amp;rsquo;t be bothered by an addition of more liquid or powder. Exception is macarons. See that link for my pointers on that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matcha Raindrop Cake</title>
      <link>https://www.mariozeats.com/post/matcharaindropcake/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 17:41:56 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mariozeats.com/post/matcharaindropcake/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7841/33583908008_7a6fabde9c_b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Matcha Raindrop Cake&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Name is a slight misnomer since it&amp;rsquo;s just a normal raindrop cake with matcha and not a matcha flavored one :p. Raindrop cakes are basically just like eating water jello. haha. BUT, with a good sauce and powder they can be super elevated :D. Took me a while to find a ratio, but this is what worked in my hands.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Raindrop Cake:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 g agar agar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;10 g sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;360 g filtered water&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add everything into a pot and heat up want until it just starts to boil and everything is dissolved.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cool down and pour into round bottomed small containers or hemisphere molds.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Let cool in the fridge.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If using cherry blossoms, add those in right after you fill the molds.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Be careful when unmolding.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Matcha Kinako blend:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Passionfruit Mochi</title>
      <link>https://www.mariozeats.com/post/passionfruitmochi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 11:24:52 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mariozeats.com/post/passionfruitmochi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4713/39798992632_79144a556e_b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Passionfruit Mochi&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently tried &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.siftandsimmer.com/matcha-brownie-mochi-brochi/&#34;&gt;Sift &amp;amp; Simmmer&amp;rsquo;s Matcha Brochi recipe&lt;/a&gt; and wanted to try it again with a different flavor, using the things I learned from the first time. I had mentioned in my Instagram comments that I wanted to try passionfruit, so I went for it! Topped it off with different things. My favorite was the raspberry powder! Here&amp;rsquo;s the adapted recipe. It&amp;rsquo;s a brochi, I guess, but I&amp;rsquo;ll call it mochi here :p.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mousses</title>
      <link>https://www.mariozeats.com/post/mousse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 15:24:07 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mariozeats.com/post/mousse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wish I was good at making mousses. I&amp;rsquo;m not. But I have a few recipes that work well enough. I wish I knew how to make the kind that legit Russian bakers use in their mousse cakes. OH WELLS. I adapted the mousse cake mousses from &lt;a href=&#34;http://verdadedesabor.blogspot.ru/2016/04/torta-rubus.html&#34;&gt;Verdade de sabor: torta rubus&lt;/a&gt;. Not sure where I first got the tart mousse recipe from :o.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For these, you can easily replace flavors by subbing out flavors/ powders/ purees.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swiss Meringue Buttercream</title>
      <link>https://www.mariozeats.com/post/smbc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 15:24:07 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mariozeats.com/post/smbc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lots of people use buttercreams for macarons. I don&amp;rsquo;t because I always kill it. But I do use buttercreams for cakes if I need them to be stable (I usually prefer whipped creams since they&amp;rsquo;re light and not too sweet). For buttercreams though, you should do a Swiss Meringue if you want something that&amp;rsquo;s light. Never make an American one since those are all sugar! :p. They&amp;rsquo;re easy to flavor as well. Literally just add whatever flavor you want to the base. I didn&amp;rsquo;t adapt this recipe. I just make as is from &lt;a href=&#34;https://livforcake.com/swiss-meringue-buttercream-recipe/&#34;&gt;Liv for Cake&lt;/a&gt;. I suggest just going to her website because you can adjust serving sizes and make US or metric!&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ll still list it, but yeah, just go there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
