<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Strawberry on Mario&#39;z Eats</title>
    <link>https://www.mariozeats.com/tags/strawberry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Strawberry on Mario&#39;z Eats</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:13:48 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.mariozeats.com/tags/strawberry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Charcoal Matcha Strawberry Roll Cake</title>
      <link>https://www.mariozeats.com/post/charcoalmatcharollcake/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:13:48 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mariozeats.com/post/charcoalmatcharollcake/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4205/35079019270_a17bb8d5f6_h.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Charcoal Matcha Roll Cake&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently bought some activated charcoal since I saw so many places on IG using it! And then I saw a roll cake with matcha filling and knew I should try doing that! The filling was not stable enough to support the cake, so the cake sort of broke :(. I think actually rolling the cake like swirl may have been a better option. I also made a charcoal sablé and tried to incorporate it, but it really didn&amp;rsquo;t add much. That recipe was equal parts butter, granulated sugar, and almond flour with a tiny bit of charcoal heated in the oven until baked.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matcha Strawberry Sponge Cake</title>
      <link>https://www.mariozeats.com/post/matchastrawberryspongecake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 17:40:45 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mariozeats.com/post/matchastrawberryspongecake/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;![Matcha Strawberry Cake]https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4206/34656124263_b2e24249c2_h.jpg)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are 5 main components for the cake, including the macarons (green tea sponge, whipped cream frosting, green tea glaze, green tea macaron shells, strawberry curd filling). The optimal timeline is probably: make the cake and whipped cream and assemble and chill. Make mirror glaze and cool to RT. While that&amp;rsquo;s cooling, make the macarons.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Matcha Sponge : [makes 1 jelly roll sheet]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;112g cake flour&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tsp baking powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;16 g matcha powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/4 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;5 large eggs, separated&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;156 g granulated sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;60 g whole milk&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Oven at 400F. Line baking sheet with parchment paper or silpat&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Whisk together sifted flour, baking powder, green tea and salt.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a different, large bowl, whisk egg yolks, sugar, and milk until pale.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Separately, whisk egg whites until medium stiff peaks (if you whisk too stiff, it&amp;rsquo;s harder to incorporate).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add dry mixture to wet mixture and fold together. Then slowly fold in the medium stiff egg whites.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pour batter onto the baking sheet and then rap the sheet down a few times to release any big air bubbles.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bake for 9 minutes (a toothpick should go in and out cleanly).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Using a knife or something thin, move along the edge of the pan and cake. Remove cake from pan and silpat and let cool on a baking rack.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m guesstimating on amounts for the whipped cream frosting. To make it stabilized, just make a corn starch paste first and add enough to make the whipped cream firm. Also sugar can always be adjusted based on your sweetness preferences.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Stabilized Whipped Cream Frosting:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
